<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>com.pocoguy.Muse</id>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-3.0-or-later</project_license>
  <name>Mixtapes</name>
  <summary>A modern, Linux-first YouTube Music player</summary>

  <description>
    <p>
      Mixtapes is a YouTube Music player built with GTK4 and Libadwaita for Linux.
      Browse your library, search for music, create playlists, and enjoy seamless playback
      with MPRIS integration, responsive mobile-friendly design, and background playback.
    </p>
    <p>
      Note: This software is in alpha stage. It is not affiliated with YouTube or Google.
    </p>
  </description>

  <developer id="com.pocoguy">
    <name>Mohamad Obeid</name>
  </developer>

  <launchable type="desktop-id">com.pocoguy.Muse.desktop</launchable>

  <url type="homepage">https://github.com/m-obeid/Mixtapes</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/m-obeid/Mixtapes/issues</url>
  <url type="vcs-browser">https://github.com/m-obeid/Mixtapes</url>

  <supports>
    <control>pointing</control>
    <control>keyboard</control>
    <control>touch</control>
  </supports>

  <recommends>
    <display_length compare="ge">360</display_length>
  </recommends>

  <requires>
    <display_length compare="ge">360</display_length>
  </requires>

  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <caption>Library page in grid view</caption>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/m-obeid/Mixtapes/main/screenshots/9.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <caption>Playlist page and open queue</caption>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/m-obeid/Mixtapes/main/screenshots/1.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <caption>Artist page</caption>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/m-obeid/Mixtapes/main/screenshots/2.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <caption>Album page</caption>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/m-obeid/Mixtapes/main/screenshots/3.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <caption>Search results</caption>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/m-obeid/Mixtapes/main/screenshots/4.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <caption>Mobile expanded player</caption>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/m-obeid/Mixtapes/main/screenshots/5.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <caption>Mobile queue</caption>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/m-obeid/Mixtapes/main/screenshots/6.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <caption>Mobile artist page</caption>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/m-obeid/Mixtapes/main/screenshots/7.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <caption>Mobile album page</caption>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/m-obeid/Mixtapes/main/screenshots/8.png</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>

  <content_rating type="oars-1.1"/>

  <releases>
    <release version="2026-23-04.0" date="2026-04-23">
      <description>
        <p>Major feature update with UI changes, history, and more.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Complete UI overhaul for better desktop experience and consistent maximum width for the view contents</li>
          <li>History implemented</li>
          <li>New Avatar icon replaces the hamburger menu</li>
          <li>Discord RPC: added more options in the settings to customize appearence</li>
          <li>Play Next and Add to Queue options in song context menus, playlist row context menus, and playlist/album header menus</li>
          <li>More caching for better performance and responsiveness</li>
          <li>Added preferences to change renderer in case of GPU acceleration issues</li>
          <li>Added preference to control sidebar position (left/right).</li>
          <li>Added preference for folder structure in downloads.</li>
          <li>Added ability to search within library</li>
          <li>Added ability to change between grid and list view for library</li>
          <li>Fixed bug where download would override M3U with incomplete tracklist</li>
          <li>Added expanded cover view for large screens</li>
          <li>Added refresh to some pages</li> 
          <li>Smaller fixes</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2026-18-04.0" date="2026-04-18">
      <description>
        <p>New app icon, Discord RPC improvements, queue management, and bug fixes.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>New app icon with proper symbolic and devel variants</li>
          <li>Windows ICO now has transparency and all standard resolutions (16-256px)</li>
          <li>Discord RPC: fix status display field name (status_display_type) so artist/song shows under username</li>
          <li>Discord RPC: configurable status display type (app name, artist, or song title) in preferences</li>
          <li>Discord RPC: enable/disable toggle in preferences with connection status indicator</li>
          <li>Discord RPC: album name now shown in rich presence instead of repeating song title</li>
          <li>Play Next and Add to Queue options in song context menus, playlist row context menus, and playlist/album header menus</li>
          <li>Album name displayed in search results alongside artist</li>
          <li>Missing album names fetched in background for search results</li>
          <li>Refresh Metadata option in song row and expanded player menus</li>
          <li>Maybe fixed: playlist background fetch race condition that could cause segfaults</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2026-11-04.0" date="2026-11-04">
      <description>
        <p>Discord Rich Presence support and a stack of stability fixes around fast skipping, the queue, and the explore page.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Discord Rich Presence: now playing track with album art, small Mixtapes icon, and live progress bar (cross-platform: Linux, macOS, Windows)</li>
          <li>Start Radio from any playlist or album via the more menu</li>
          <li>Fast-skip stability: spamming next no longer wraps the queue back to the first track</li>
          <li>Fix: clicking a song in a playlist could silently play the first track when the click target wasn't found in the queue</li>
          <li>Fix: removing a song from the queue now updates the queue panel immediately instead of waiting for the next track change</li>
          <li>Fix: rare segfault when switching songs from the queue panel</li>
          <li>Fix: volume could snap back to 100% on track change due to a spurious GStreamer notify-volume during pipeline rebuilds</li>
          <li>Explore tab now retries automatically on transient network errors at startup and shows a manual retry button if it still fails</li>
          <li>Expanded player carousel no longer drags playback back to the first track when songs are skipped rapidly</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2026-05-04.0" date="2026-05-04">
      <description>
        <p>This update adds the ability to download songs as local files with all the metadata and offline listening, as well as Charts in the Explore page.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2026-04-04.0" date="2026-04-04">
      <description>
        <p>Major feature update with library management, uploads, and performance improvements.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Changed versioning scheme for Alpha releases to YYYY-MM-DD.p where p is the patch number</li>
          <li>Stream URL caching for instant song replay and pre-caching of surrounding queue songs</li>
          <li>Multi-select songs in playlists with bulk actions (add to playlist, remove, play selected)</li>
          <li>Sort playlists by title, artist, album, or duration with ascending/descending toggle</li>
          <li>Search within playlists now covers all tracks, not just loaded ones</li>
          <li>Save and unsave albums and playlists to your library</li>
          <li>Saved albums section in the library</li>
          <li>Upload songs to YouTube Music</li>
          <li>Uploaded music tab with albums, artists, and all-songs view</li>
          <li>Delete individual uploaded songs and albums with confirmation</li>
          <li>Start radio from any song, artist, or search result</li>
          <li>Artist page now shows full videos list, playlists, featured on, and fans might also like sections</li>
          <li>YouTube channel support (non-artist channels with playlists and videos)</li>
          <li>Read more/show less for long descriptions on album, playlist, and artist pages</li>
          <li>Copy link with toast notification across the app</li>
          <li>Add to playlist from queue panel and expanded player</li>
          <li>Playlist duration calculated from all tracks, not just loaded ones</li>
          <li>Background playback - music continues when window is closed, reopen via MPRIS</li>
          <li>Volume slider now matches system mixer percentage with bidirectional sync</li>
          <li>Fixed volume feedback loop that could freeze the system</li>
          <li>Fixed song activation playing wrong track due to expanded player carousel race condition</li>
          <li>Fixed queue panel selection issues causing unintended track changes</li>
          <li>Responsive cover art sizing with proper desktop and mobile dimensions</li>
          <li>Consistent search result row heights</li>
          <li>Custom playlist cover upload support fixed</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.1.0-alpha" date="2026-02-20">
      <description>
        <p>Initial alpha release</p>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
</component>
